# **Justin Dao**

## **Software Developer**

## **About Me**

Skilled Software Developer transitioning from Finance with 6.5 years of working experience. Possesses strong analytical, creative problem-solving skills, with ability to develop and execute well thought out decisions under pressure. Willing to accept responsibilities beyond immediate job duties and take on special projects.

## **Programming Experience**

Student 2022

#### **Nucamp Coding Bootcamp, Software Engineering Program**

- Immersive training program with an emphasis on Full Stack Web Development
- Utilized MERN stack to create 2 Projects, including web and mobile applications, and 1 React Project
  - WhatTheFork: Mobile Application
    - Developed interactive end-to-end mobile application with React Native for front-end, utilizing Redux for state management. Implemented Express and Node.js for server-side operations, managing HTTP requests, and user authentication via JWT (JSON Web Token). Leveraged MongoDB and Mongoose for robust data storage and retrieval, enabling features such as user registration, profile management, recipe searching, rating, and bookmarking. This project showcased proficiency in full-stack development, efficient state management, and secure user authentication. Frontend hosted on Netlify, Backend hosted on Heroku.
  - o NitroFit: Web Application
    - Designed a robust Fitness App using React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, and Express.js. Leveraged Formik and React Router for enhanced UX, and implemented UI with reactstrap. Established secure user authentication using bcrypt.js and JWT. Managed MongoDB operations via Mongoose and maintained app security with dotenv. Developed RESTful APIs for user registration and login, and integrated social media using Font Awesome. Frontend hosted on Netlify, Backend hosted on Heroku.

## **Work Experience**

#### Financial Analyst II

#### **Exemplis**

- Promoted from FA I (2018-2021)
- Revenue-Tech Lead
  - Leveraged Power BI and SQL Data Reader to conduct quantitative analysis to forecast revenue, identify future trends and assess risk associated with Target execution
  - Analyzed product performance trends across different verticals, monitored industry dynamics and overall competitive landscape
- Freight-Tech Lead
  - Developed a suite of new and innovative reporting for Inbound/Outbound tracking, KPI's,
    Trend and variance analytics through Power BI and Excel
  - Aided in automating data collection to supply backend data for frontend analytics
  - Utilized OLAP cube data to pull and analyze data for Root Cause analysis
  - o Responds to financial/technical requests from Logistics VP & Sr. Manager as needed

## **Contact**

Justindao549@gmail.com



Yorba Linda, CA (714)-742-5884



When



www.linkedin.com/in/justindao1



https://github.com/justindao549

## **Skills**

#### **Technological Aptitude**

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- React.js
- MongoDB
- SQL
- PineScript
- Excel (Advanced)
- Power BI
- SQL Data Reader
- Tableau
- AX
- Prophix
- SAP

#### **Attributes**

2017-2021

- Resiliency
- Honesty
- Communication
- Creativity
- Critical Thinking
- Time Management
- Teamwork

## References

## **Work Experience Cont.**

#### Financial Analyst I

#### 2015-2017

2011-2015

2022

#### **Hyundai Motor Group**

Forecast IT costs for all North American business units of Hyundai Motors Group (\$50M annual

- Contributed Savings of \$1.5M to 2016 OPEX Overall [\$5.0M]
  - Performed cost saving strategies by utilizing Prophix) such as ACQ vs Lease, Lease Ext. vs Buyout, & Lease Refresh
  - Reduced costs through "True-Up" Analysis to remove extraneous (72) Licenses
- Took lead in Creating Budget Transfer Workflow on SharePoint
  - Approved by Executives & is now a Companywide process at
  - Increased speed of Approvals (from average 10.5 working days to 2.83 working days)
  - Lead to overall increase in OPEX process efficiency (from 35-45 days to 27-35 days)

## **Education**

- Bachelor of Business Admin, California State University, Fullerton
- NuCamp Bootcamp (Full Stack Web + Mobile Development)

Justindao549@gmail.com



Yorba Linda, CA



When

**Contact** 



www.linkedin.com/in/justindao1



https://github.com/justindao549

## **Skills**

#### **Technological Aptitude**

- JavaScript
- **HTML**
- **CSS**
- React.js
- MongoDB
- SQL
- PineScript
- Excel (Advanced)
- Power BI
- **SQL** Data Reader
- Tableau
- ΑХ
- Prophix
- SAP

#### **Attributes**

- Resiliency
- Honesty
- Communication
- Creativity
- **Critical Thinking**
- Time Management
- Teamwork

## References